cosmeticsdatabase.com 2016-06-29

# Privacy Policy | EWG

Updated March 2016.  This policy updates and overrides any preexisting policies found on any EWG web properties.

The Environmental Working Group will automatically add you to our database of supporters when you participate in any EWG, EWG Action Fund, or Healthy Child Healthy World campaign or promotion. If you do not wish to be on this list, you may unsubscribe at any time, and we will make that option easily and readily available. **EWG will never sell your e-mail address or other contact information.**

##  Information Collected

####  LOG FILES

Like most websites, EWG servers may record the numerical Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the browser software you use and your operating system; the time and date you access EWG’s website; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site. EWG uses this information to measure the number of visitors to various sections of the site, to diagnose and correct system errors, and to improve the site. No information that identifies you personally is collected in our server logs. 

####  USE OF COOKIES

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. Cookies must be turned on to use certain interactive content on EWG’s website. We use cookies to store basic information and preferences so we can customize the user experience. No information that identifies you personally is stored in a cookie. To learn more about cookies, visit http://www.getnetwise.org/glossary.php#cookie.

####  GOOGLE SERVICES

EWG uses Google Analytics for analysis of website traffic and trends. We have enabled Google Analytics Demographics to monitor age, gender and interests of site visitors in the aggregate in order to tailor content and campaigns for our audience. No personal information about individual visitors is obtained, stored or accessed by EWG in this process. 

EWG uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online to visitors who have come to our sites. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show EWG ads on sites across the Internet to visitors with the EWG remarketing cookie. EWG and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, improve and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to EWG websites. 

Individuals can use Google’s Ads Settings to opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads to their interests. 

####  SUBSCRIBER INFORMATION AND “CONTACT US” FORMS

Information submitted by users via the “Contact Us” page listed next to the mailing address at the bottom of our website comes to EWG in the form of an email. EWG will store your email address in its database of supporters if: (1) you elect to receive our email updates when you use our web-based form to contact us, or (2) if you participate in any EWG, EWG Action Fund, or Healthy Child Healthy World campaign or promotion. EWG does not collect any information other than what the supporter provides on our forms. If you would like to review your personal information collected, make corrections, and/or request that your information not be shared with third parties, please contact us at (202) 667-6982. Requests are usually processed within several working days. 

####  DOES EWG COLLECT INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN? 

EWG’s web properties are not intended for use by children under 13 years of age. EWG does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to EWG, including your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address. In the event that EWG learns that EWG has collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, EWG will delete that information. If you believe that EWG might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at 202-667-6982.  

####  SECURITY 

EWG uses industry standard, HTTPS protocol for secure encryption and submission of the personal and credit card data you provide voluntarily on our websites. EWG stores the personal information submitted in a secure, private database to which only EWG, its sister organization EWG Action Fund, and their agents have access. EWG does not store in this database nor do we have access to the credit card numbers from online donations or purchases through our site. 

##  Information Use

####  E-MAIL COMMUNICATIONS

Subscriber information will be used by EWG and its sister organization, EWG Action Fund, to send out messages about the organization's work, advocacy, and related issues.

####  SHARING SUBSCRIBER INFORMATION

EWG reserves the right to share subscriber information with EWG's sister organization, EWG Action Fund, as well as its agents. Otherwise, EWG will not share personally identifiable information with a third party, except in the unlikely event that it is required by law or if we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a court order or legal process served on our website. 

####  COMMUNICATIONS FROM WEBSITE

EWG sends new supporters a welcome email to explain what you can expect to receive from us. In addition, EWG and EWG Action Fund send supporters periodic emails with information and links to our website and other related content. EWG and EWG Action Fund also send supporters information about events, action campaigns, and fundraising efforts.

####  SUBSCRIPTION TERMINATION

Supporters may unsubscribe from our email updates at any time. Links to unsubscribe are included at the bottom of every EWG and EWG Action Fund blast e-mail communication. If you are unable to complete your request using our automated system, please contact us at (202) 667-6982. Requests are usually processed within several working days.

####  LINKS

EWG’s website may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that EWG is not responsible for the privacy practices of those other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by EWG’s website.

####  CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

If EWG decides to change its privacy policy, we will post these changes to this statement, to the [**www.ewg.org**](http://www.ewg.org/) homepage, and to any other places we deem appropriate to ensure that our users will always know what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we share it.

If we wish to use supporters’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify supporters via email. Supporters will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.

####  CONTACT INFORMATION

For questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Phone: (202) 667-6982

Fax: (202) 232-2592

Postal Address: 1436 U Street, NW, Ste. 100, Washington, DC 20009
